

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Cloud Solution Design & Architect seeking roles in IT Infrastructure Management in Cloud Administration, Cloud Consulting, Cloud Presales and Onsite/Offshore Cloud Deployment and Cloud Solution Architect job role.

Current Designation: CLOUD SOLUTION DESIGN &

ARCHITECT

Current Company: Tata Consultancy Services

Current Location: Kolkata

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Pune, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance Role: System Admin

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Cloud Solution Design & Architect, System Admin, IT Infrastructure Management, Business Analysis, Cloud Computing, Project Management, Quality Assurance, Agile Methodology, AWS, Mcrosoft Azure, Oracle Cloud, Private

Total Experience: 14 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MBA/PGDM [Operations]

Notice Period: 3 Months

Cloud, Public Cloud, Hybrid Cloud, HTML, CSS

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

14+ years of experience in Operations and IT. I am multi-cloud certified in Mcrosoft Azure, AWS and Oracle Cloud. Throughout my career I have been in multiple roles and responsibilities. I am also certified Professional Scrum Master, PRINCE2 Certified Project Manager and holds Six Sigma Lean and Green Belt Certification. My digital portfolio provides the details of my career, works and projects that I have accomplished. I am an avid learner in Cloud technology and enthusiast about designing and deploying cloud solutions. I have worked as Quality Analyst, Project Delivery Manager, Transition Manager, Scrum Master, Developer, Business Analyst and Design architect. Currently looking for Cloud Architect Consultant/ Solution Architect/Pre-Sales role in public, private and hybrid cloud.

Work Experience

Tata Consultancy Services as CLOUD SOLUTION DESIGN & ARCHITECT May 2012 to Till Date

Cloud Infrastructure, Architecting, Design and Deployment
Designing data ingestion from on-premise and cloud sources into development.
Deployment Summary- Web Server, App Services, Application Gateway, WAF
VM, Auto-Scaling, VM Scale sets, Load Balancer
DNS, CDN, Traffic Management
Data Storage, Backups
Disaster Recovery, Data Migration
Active Directory, Federation
IAM, Cloud Monitoring & Security
Virtual Networks, VPN, Security Rules, Routing
Cloud Automation

IBM as QUALITY ANALYST Sep 2008 to Mar 2012

Quality Analyst in Retail and Supply Chain Operations
Responsibilities: Process Audit, Responsible for overall Process Quality Management
Driving Innovation, Building Quality Team
Internal Audit and Compliance Management
Executed LEAN Six Sigma Yellow Belt Project in improving Contact Centre Experience

Genpact as Process Associate
 Oct 2006 to Sep 2008
 Worked in Credit Card Operations with GE Money, Australia



Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Education

UG: B.Sc (Environmental science) from Calcutta University in 2006

PG: MBA/PGDM (Operations) from Symbiosis Centre for Distance Learning (SCDL) in 2010

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Six Sigma Yellow Belt Certification

Certified Lean Practitioner

Lean Six Sigma Green Belt Certification

PRINCE2 Practitioner Certification

Professional Scrum Master

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals

Microsoft Azure Administrator Associate

Master Cloud Architect Program "Azure-AWS-GCP"

Certified Oracle Autonomous Database Specialist

Certified Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Architect Associate

Certified Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Solution Architect Professional

Microsoft Azure Architect Technologies Certified

Microsoft Azure Solution Architect Design Expert

AWS Cloud Practitioner

AWS Solution Architect Associate

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience	
Microsoft Azure		3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
AWS		3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Oracle Cloud		2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Various Cloud Services		3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
WORDPRESS		5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Google Cloud (GCP)		1 Year(s) 6 Month(s)	
Scrum Master	0	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
PROJECT MANAGEMENT	0	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No**

Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.